

# CONTACT

hello@markboss.me @

markboss.me

linkedin.com/in/markbboss in

## **ABOUT ME**

I am a researcher at Unity Technologies. Before that, I was a Ph.D. student at the University of Tübingen in the computer graphics group of Prof. Hendrik Lensch. My research interests lie at the intersection of machine learning and computer graphics, with the main focus on inferring physical properties (shape, material, illumination, etc.) from images.

## **EDUCATION**

#### Ph.D. Student

*Jun. 2018 - Jun. 2022*University of Tübingen, Germany Advisor: Prof. Hendrik Lensch

### Master of Science (M.Sc.)

Feb. 2016 - Apr. 2018 University of Tübingen, Germany

## Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.)

Sep. 2012 - Feb. 2016 Osnabrück University of Applied Sciences, Germany

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Senior Research Scientist - Unity Technologies - Germany

Sep. 2022 - present

Student Researcher - Google - Germany

Jun. 2021 - Apr. 2022

Research Intern - NVIDIA - Westford, MA

Apr. 2019 - Jul. 2019

Android Developer - zahlz - Osnabrück, Germany

Jul. 2015 - Jun. 2017

# **SELECTED PUBLICATIONS**

# SAMURAI: Shape And Material from Unconstrained Real-world Arbitrary Image collections

May 2022 - arXiv - Mark Boss, Andreas Engelhardt, Abhishek Kar, Yuanzhen Li, Deqing Sun, Jonathan T. Barron, Hendrik P. A. Lensch, Varun Jampani

## Neural-PIL: Neural Pre-Integrated Lighting for Reflectance Decomposition

Dec. 2021 - NeurIPS - Mark Boss, Varun Jampani, Raphael Braun, Ce Liu, Jonathan T. Barron, Hendrik P. A. Lensch

## **NeRD: Neural Reflectance Decomposition from Image Collections**

Oct. 2021 - ICCV - Mark Boss, Raphael Braun, Varun Jampani, Jonathan T. Barron, Ce Liu, Hendrik P. A. Lensch

## Two-shot Spatially-varying BRDF and Shape Estimation

Jun. 2020 - CVPR - Mark Boss, Varun Jampani, Kihwan Kim, Hendrik P. A. Lensch, Jan Kautz